We've got like million token, two
million token context windows. And if
you have 10 smart things to say and you
say all of them, each of them will get
less attention than if you said three of
them. This is a little sample to-do
application with a Jurassic theme and
asking the agent to add an edit button
and it loads that code and reads that
into context. However, it created this
blue edit button and that doesn't fit my
beautiful Jurassic theme. So, we can add
explicit context that doesn't rely on
agentic search like an agent MD file
says, "Always stick to the theme
colors." This is nice. Typically, you
have a lot more to say and so this is a
problem.
[Music]
One common pattern is the separation
between rules and knowledge. Rules would
be a small amount of data that you're
providing it that you're kind of shoving
down their throat. You're saying this
will be in your agent MD. You're going
to see this every single time and they
have to be succinct. And what they
should do is they should include links
and references to guide agentic search
around where it can it fetch additional
information and that is the knowledge.
And I'll give an example from Tessell's
content. So, hopefully many people on
this
in this event
here or virtually know that Tessell has
a spec registry and we it's a a
dependency system for knowledge. You can
publish context into it in this form we
call tiles and then you can consume that
down to your to your consumers, right?
To your agents
and it will adapt it to the local agent.
And you can do it for your context, but
we also pre-populated the registry with
over 10,000 specs
or context that
that helps agents use open source
libraries better. We've analyzed those
libraries. We've iterated. We've
evaluated and we curated those. So,
let's let's look a little bit at what is
the structure of those.
Um in in first of all, we define a
knowledge base. So, well, what is the
knowledge that you want? So, you do that
in this tessell.json file in our
example. There are variations of it
we'll touch
to say this is the information I want.
In this case, I have a bunch of
libraries I want to know how to use
them. And then you'll see that each one
of those is fragmented into pieces. So,
the agent doesn't need to suck it all up
right away. Especially for some of these
libraries, there's a lot to say. You
don't want to hog the context window.
So, there's a bunch of different files.
The second thing we would do is we will
put a little bit of knowledge a little
bit of rules in the agent MD file and
we'll say, "Here's a link to your
knowledge." We actually it's a bit
longer over here, but we also give a
little bit of instruction of
what is the structure of the knowledge
you might find to the agent, but it's a
very small amount of context that is in
the rules that always loaded. And then
if you click that knowledge MD file, you
will get a markdown file that the agent
can easily find out which libraries do
you have a little bit of information
about them and where can it learn more.
And then down the rabbit hole
it can learn more. It has an index file
it explains about in this case Next.js
and then it can in that file find links
to additional information. So, this is
like a human clicking links on a
website, right? You have a summary
thing. You're expanding a section or
you're clicking through and it's very
effective. This is a good way to give
the agent
a way to find the right information
leaning to its agentic search
capabilities, but don't ask it to to
sort of browse the web and just figure
it out.
So, hopefully this points you're saying,
"Well, show me some data." I realized as
I was building it that this is a Jerry
Maguire reference and not everybody
knows that. It might be like a my agent
is starting to defer of it like a it
does say show me the money typically.
Um so, okay. Can we see some data,
right? I make this claim that this is a
good way and a good effective way to to
make the agents work. Let's see some
data. I'll show two examples of this.
First is thanks to the great work that
the team at Vercel has done on Next.js.
So, Next.js is a very well well-used,
JavaScript framework that is maintained
and built today by the Vercel team.
And they published as a thought leader
in the AI space
a benchmark about that tries to measure
how well can agents use Next.js. And
they created about 50 different test
cases
and
they ran it through different agents to
see how well they can address those.
It's interesting by the way immediately
to see that even though Next.js is so
popular and has so much content. It's
like the sweetheart of the training
data, right? It's well-documented. It's
an amazingly like clear set of data. The
top agents, the ones that did the best
still only got a 42% score in this
benchmark. And so, that's already
interesting and a bit sobering, but it
goes to show okay, can we improve this
with context engineering and in general
that if you measure this now, I bet you
all the agents are now working on
optimizing it.
And so, our question was, "Okay, we've
done this. Can we optimize this with
context? Can we test our
our our knowledge like these tiles that
we create? Do they actually make it
better?" And we ran this eval cuz we
already had the eval. So, we just had to
compare the two test cases and we're
happy to see that yes, yes, we can. With
the knowledge, the success rate like for
us it was about 40% in our
test environments success rate of using
SJS on this benchmark, it jumped up to
92% if we got that info. This is if we
got, you know, the very thoroughly
created piece of information, but we
also find for instance that a smaller
prompt midway that just guides the agent
to look at the things that you care
about
in this case some linting and some build
errors actually also bumped up the
process substantially. So, sometimes
it's knowledge and sometimes it's
steering around what is it to pay
attention to.
This is great for Next.js, but this was
a very thorough benchmark set that
required a lot of attention. We can't do
that for everything. But what you can do
when you evaluate your content and when
you have something that is
you don't have these sort of the
bandwidth to create a deep benchmark for
is that you can use LLMs to create
evaluation data.
And so, we took 270 random libraries and
we asked to the LLM to create test
exercises for them.
A scorecard to evaluate how well they
did on that test and then we ran it
through agents. The data I have here is
for Claude code. We saw similar data for
Cursor.
And then eventually you ask an LLM to
judge the result with that rubric. And
indeed when we ran that, we saw that on
average across those 270, we bumped up
the success rate from about 60% to about
81%
in open source in agents' ability to
consume open source across these 270
libraries and we did that with a little
bit of a shortening of the time. So, the
agents were a lot more successful in a
little bit less time, a little bit
faster, which was really encouraging.
So, this is great and this is again the
validation part. We also had you always
find these little bits of information
that you don't know how to expect.
Some interesting information about the
age of a library.
And so, this graph shows with the same
test the success rate of the agent. This
is Claude code across
correlated to the age of the libraries.
The libraries at the left are the
oldest. The libraries on the right are
the newest. That this is release date
just as a simple measure. And it's
interesting to see how the libraries
that are 5 to 10 years old, those are
the ones that the agents do the best
with and we've seen this with other
agents as well
and the distance is substantial and that
makes sense because very old libraries
they might have they might have
confusing information on the web. Maybe
they don't have as much web
representation if they're truly old and
the very new libraries often times they
haven't accumulated enough information
on the web and some of their data is
actually after the training data.
And our theory was that with with the
tiles, we actually can flatten that
line, right? We cuz we give them the
information. They have it. So, they
should use it and they did. We've seen
that we elevate the result more broadly.
And this was useful cuz it matches our
kind of anecdotal experience that
um
using this type of knowledge, using the
right context sometimes just helps and
sometimes it turns it from it doesn't
work to it works.